[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
Now, in contrast, let's make it more personalized,
现在 与之前不同 让我们弄得更个性化一点
a model that's more personalized, as Emily, described.
这次的模型要像艾米莉描述的那样更个性化
So, next we are gonna build a a song
那么下一步我们将搭建一个
recommender with personalization.
个性化歌曲推荐系统
So let's call it personalize_model and
让我们把它命名为personalize_model并且
all we're gonna do is repeat the line
我们只需重复之前的命令行
that we had earlier so graphlab.,
因此首先载入graphlab
instead of being the popularity model,
只是这次不用流行度模型
let's use the item similarity recommender,
而是使用相似度推荐器
so remember we talked about item similarity in the module.
要记得我们在模块中讨论过的各项相似性
We can do a item_similarity.create.
我们可以调用一次item_similarity.create
And let's see what happens.
现在让我们来看会发生什么现在让我们来看会发生什么
So here, just like before, we had to give it train_data.
在这里，像之前一样，我们要输入训练数据train_data
We have to tell it what the user_id column is called,
我们要指明那一列是用户名
which in this case was user_id.
本例中它就叫user_id
And you had to tell it what the item_id column in this case which is called song.
你还需要给出条目列也就是这里的标记为song的那一列
So instead of the popularity model we now built an item_similarity model.
那么现在我们要搭建一个基于条目相似性而不是流行度的模型
And here we go it's done.
搭好了
So let's start applying it.
那么让我们开始使用它吧
So, applying the personalized
那么 使用这个个性化的
model to make song recommendations.
模型来推荐歌曲
And here we go, let's apply it.
让我们开始吧
So let's start with the couple of users that we had before.
首先从我们之前用到的那些用户开始着手
So for example if you take the personalized model,
比方说 如果你拿这个叫做personalized_model个性化模型
personalized_model and we call recommend
用来对第一个用户也就是0号用户
on that for that first user so users of 0.
调用推荐函数
You'll see that no longer does it recommend Bjork and
你会看到它不再推荐比约克和
a few of those others that everybody got, but
那些之前所有人都得到的少数推荐了
recommended Dr. Feelgood, Elizeth Cardoso, and
取而代之的是Dr. Feelgood, Elizeth Cardoso和
then the Brazilian song, Ween, Subhumans and so on.
一些巴西歌曲 Ween啊Subhumans啊等等这些歌手的歌
It's kind of an interesting thing so pretty cool.
这个结果有些意思而且挺酷的
Let's see what user one got because it's a personalized_model.
让我们来看看第一号用户得到的结果 因为这是一个个性化的模型
So personalized_model.recommend for users.
所以它的推荐是针对用户的
And again it's a list but I'm just gonna put one element in the list, so user 1.
这次要输入一个列表 我把1号用户这个元素放进列表里
And you'll see that now it recommends something totally different.
你可以看到这次它推荐的东西完全不同
Florence and the Machine,
弗洛伦萨机进分子 译者注：此为一英国独立乐队
and somehow this user really likes Florence and the Machine.
不知道为什么 这个用户真的很喜欢弗洛伦萨机进分子
[LAUGH] It just recommends that again, again, again, again, again.
[笑] 它一直不停地推荐这个乐队的歌
And Apocalyptica and so on.
还有金属启示录等等 (芬兰乐队)
So as you can see, now the model is really personalized.
所以你可以看到 现在这个模型是真的个性化
And you can do some really fun things with it because it's personalized.
因为它是个性化的 你可以用它来干点很有意思的事情
Not only can you say for a particular user, what songs,
你不仅可以找出某个特定用户喜欢什么歌
other songs they should listen to, just like we did in recommendations.
他们应该会挺哪些其他的歌曲 就像我们的推荐系统所做的那样
But we can also take a song and
我们还可以以一个歌曲为单位
ask what other songs are similar, are liked by similar people.
找出哪些其他的歌曲跟它相似 被相似的人群喜欢
So people who like the song also like this other song, so
那么喜欢这首歌的人也会喜欢另外这一首歌曲 因此
we can do that by personalized_model.get_similar_items.
我们可以调用 personalized_model.get_similiar_items来实现这个功能
So get similar items, you give it a list of items, and it finds similar ones.
要找到相似的条目 你首先给模型一系列初始条目 然后它会找到相似的
So for example,
举例来说，
if I really love the song with or
假如我非常喜欢这首U2的
Without You by U2.
"若即若离"
I really actually like this song, it's pretty cool.
我是真的非常喜欢这首歌 它太酷了
You'll see other songs it recommends all by U2,
你会看到它推荐了所有U2的歌
I Still Haven't Found What I'm Looking For, Hold Me, Thrill Me,
我还是没找到我想要的 "抱紧我惊呼我亲吻我杀死我"
Kiss Me, Kill Me, Window in the Skies, Vertigo,
"空中之窗"  "眩晕"
Sunday Bloody Sunday, Bad, A Day Without Me, Another Place Another Place,
"血腥星期天"  "坏" "没有我的一天" "彼时彼地"
Walk On, Walk On's a nice song, Get On Your Boots, so all U2 songs.
"继续前行" "继续前行"是首不错的歌，  "蹬上你的靴子" 基本上所有U2的歌
So if you like one U2 song, you like other U2 songs, that's pretty typical.
所以如果你喜欢U2的一首歌 那你就喜欢其它U2的歌 这还挺常见的
Now another thing that I enjoy, so if I take this
另一个我很享受的点是 如果我用这个
very similar model and I am gonna get similar items.
相似度模型我可以得到相似的条目
So we can get all similar users.
那么我们找到所有相似的用户
For a user to find other users that like this one, like her.
从某个用户开始找其它相似的用户 比如说她
But here we are gonna get similar items and
但是这里我们要找相似的天目
the list I'm gonna give is a little different.
因此这次我输入的列表会有所不同
So this is another song I kinda like.
那么这里是另外一首我还挺喜欢的歌
It's called Chan Chan and I like the live version.
它叫做Chan Chan 我很喜欢现场版 译者注： 这里的歌名Chan Chan 应该是人名，是歌曲中的主人公
And it is by Buena Vista Social Club.
是乐士浮生录的歌 译者注： 古巴乐队
Now if you don't know this song, if you know the Buena Vista Social Club,
如果你不知道这首歌 如果你不知道乐士浮生录
you should it's awesome, awesome really, cool.
你应该去了解一下 这首歌真的非常非常酷
So if you like Chan Chan, by Buena Vista Social Club, a Cuban band,
那如果你喜欢古巴乐队乐士浮生录的Chan Chan
you also might like other Buena Vista Social Club songs.
你可能也会喜欢其它乐士浮生录的歌
Amor de Loca Juventud and others.
比如奥马尔德洛卡尤文
You might also like this, Diferente by Gotan Project.
你可能还会喜欢这个 高登计划的"与众不同"
Gotan Project, a Argentinian band, really cool one,
高登计划是一个非常酷的阿根廷乐队
more like Gypsy Kings, Flamenco band this all makes a lot of sense.
风格有点像吉卜赛国王和弗拉门戈这两个乐队 这些都非常合理
Remember the song down here by Gotan Project, Criminal,
记住这首高登计划的"罪犯"
which I kinda like as well.
我也挺喜欢它的
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community